Seasoned software developer and architect with 16 years experience building and maintaining secure and scalable applications. Major experience with .NET/C#, SQL, JS and leading development teams. Recent experience on building cloud native applications, DevOps, microservices, .NET Core, Azure and Kubernetes.

GitHub: https://github.com/aashishkoirala Website/Blog: https://www.aashishkoirala.com

EXPERIENCE

Bond-Pro, Remote

Chief Software Architect, March 2019 – March 2020

Software architecture and development; leadership of Agile offshore team; DevOps

- Worked on building the company's flagship cloud-based offering
- Worked with .NET Core, Azure, EF Core, Kubernetes, Docker, Terraform among others

Vistra (formerly Radius), Bedford, MA

Software Architect / Technical Lead, July 2012 – March 2019

Software architecture and development; leadership of Agile offshore team; DevOps

- Helped build and oversaw cloud based, microservices driven enterprise system. Ported
 entire system from on-premises to cloud-native Azure PaaS. Rewrote service and
 security stack, rebuilt frontend using Angular and SignalR.
- Led the team that built a sophisticated global payroll system from inception to release that supported over 150 customers across over 20 countries
- Helped build a homegrown workflow orchestration system based on Service Bus messaging

Verisk Health, Waltham, MA

Software Architect / Principal Engineer / Director of Engineering, August 2008 – July 2012 *Software architecture and development; management of Agile onshore/offshore teams*

- Took over a post-acquisition, undocumented and abandoned codebase, revived and reengineering it, thus becoming the resident expert for the system which served as the company's flagship healthcare analytics platform
- Introduced standard ETL tools and practices to the BI delivery process
- Helped transition the software development process from waterfall to Agile

D2Hawkeye Services, Kathmandu, Nepal

Software Architect, November 2004 – August 2008

Software architecture and development; management of multiple development teams

 Built, delivered and maintained 12 large scale projects using various technologies (including .NET, Java, C++, SQL Server and Oracle)

EDUCATION

M.S. in Computer Systems Engineering, Boston University, Boston, MA
B.E. in Computer Engineering, Tribhuvan University Institute of Engineering, Nepal

Tools/Tech/Practices

.NET/.NET Core

C#

ASP.NET Core

EF Core

MVC, WebAPI, SignalR IdentityServer

JavaScript / TypeScript

Angular React

Node

SQL Server, T-SQL

Azure

Kubernetes, AKS

Helm Docker

Service Fabric

Microservices Twelve Factor DDD

REST

4+1/UML

Redis

ElasticSearch Azure Service Bus RabbitMQ

OAuth2/OIDC, SAML OWASP Remediation

Git

PowerShell Bash

DevOps

CI/CD, Azure DevOps Terraform, Ansible Observability FluentBit, Kibana Prometheus, Grafana OpenTracing, Jaeger

Go Kafka AWS